各位听说了吗
And did you hear?
我们最爱的高尔夫球手又上新闻了
Our favorite golfer is in the news again.
在上周末错过了一场慈善邀请赛
Missed a charity tournament over the weekend.
真不幸
Really unfortunate.
这位世界顶尖的高尔夫球手必须抽身而出
The world's top golfer had to pull out.
实际上  这是他过去五年里第一次
In fact, it's the first time he's
从某件事情中"抽身" [讽刺伍兹"偷腥门"事件]
pulled out of anything in five years.
你怎么看  汉克  我是不是应该重新挥一杆
What do you think, Hank? Should I take a mulligan?
-别  你继续  鲍比  继续  -那我可不客气了
- No, play through, Bobby. Play through. - I will, my friend.
今晚的节目精彩绝伦
We have a great show for you tonight.
卡塞尔先生
Mr. Castle.
-你好  我是凯拉  请跟我来  -好的
- Hi, I'm Kayla. Please follow me. - Sure.
我最爱的作家理查德·卡塞尔前来做客
And my favorite writer Richard Castle's joining us.
这里  卡塞尔先生
Here you go, Mr. Castle.
一会化妆师黛比
Deb, the makeup artist,
-会帮你打理一下  -谢谢你  凯拉
- will take care of you from here. - Thank you, Kayla.
还有  你跟在梦露小姐后面出场
And you're up right after Ms. Monroe.
你好  我是艾丽
Hi, it's Ellie.
里克
Rick.
我只想说一句... 哇
Can I just say... wow.
-真是不敢相信在这见到你  -是吗
- Like, I can't believe I'm meeting you right now. - Really?
是啊  你一直是我最喜欢的作家
Well, you're, like, my favorite author ever.
《希特热浪》我已经反复看了不下三遍了
I mean, I've read "Heat wave" at least three times.
你知道吗
Can I tell you,
你演的电影我全部都看过
I have seen every movie you've ever been in?
真的  但愿你没看过《毒蛇山》
Really? Oh. Not "Viper Mountain" I hope.
《毒蛇山》当然看过
Yes, "Viper mountain." Ugh.
你是那部片子里最大的亮点
You were the best thing in that movie.
蛇把你吞掉之后  那部电影就不好看了
As soon as that snake ate you, whole movie fell apart.
各位  让我们欢迎理查德·卡塞尔
Folks, please help me in welcoming Richard Castle.
里克·卡塞尔
Rick Castle.
他挺上镜嘛
Oh, he looks good.
-欢迎  -谢谢
- Welcome. - Thank you.
首先要恭喜你  《希特热浪》
First of all, congratulations on "Heat Wave"--
登顶《纽约时报》畅销书榜
"New York Times" best seller.
谢谢  我得说
Thank you. And you know what?
我很享受写这本书的过程
I really loved writing it.
平装版是在七月二十七号上市的
Well, the paperback comes out, uh, July 27th, right?
七月二十七  没错
July 27th. That's right.
而且这个故事即将被搬上大荧幕了
And it's being made into a movie.
你现在和纽约警局的凶杀警探一起工作
Now you worked with actual NYPD homicide detectives
为《希特热浪》寻找素材
to research "Heat Wave."
是的  没错
Yes, yes, I did.
但是他们始终不让我配枪
And--and they still won't let me carry a gun.
我还真不知道你在执法部门工作
I didn't know you worked with law enforcement.
-一直很喜欢当警察的  -看吧
- It's kinda my weak spot. - Hello.
服务生  该买单啦
Waiter, check please.
你们两个还都是单身吧
Well, you guys are single, right?
准确点说  已经不再单身了  鲍比
Well, actually, not anymore, Bobby.
多谢你成全我们
Thank you very much.
镜头果然会让人看上去膨胀不少
Wow. The camera really does add 10 pounds...
尤其是自信心
to his ego.
如果有位美丽的电影女星
Call me old-fashioned when
被我假冒的警务工作者身份所吸引
a beautiful movie star is impressed with
就算被人说老土我也心甘情愿了
my fake law enforcement credentials, I'm in.
你说他是不是已经开始约她了
Do you think he's asked her out yet?
以你老爸的德性  碰上这么个美女
Your father, pretty girl like that?
他没当场求婚已经算万幸了
He may have proposed by now.
今晚的节目就到这里
And that's our show for tonight.
接下来请收看《米基·瑞德深夜脱口秀》
Stay tuned for "Late talk with Mickey Reed."
我是鲍比·曼  观众们请记住
I'm Bobby Mann. Remember, folks...
魅力男生  欢乐相约明晚
the boys'll be back on duty tomorrow night.
我一直好奇他们每次
I always wonder what
靠过去的时候都说些什么
they're saying when they lean in like that.
-谢谢  -感谢你的到来
- Thank you. - Thank you for coming.
他们想取我性命
They want me dead.
-不好意思  你说什么  -我是认真的
- I'm sorry. What? - I'm serious.
你和警察一起工作  对吧
You work with cops, right?
-他们想...  -节目很精彩  伙计们
- They want-- - That was a great show, guys.
对于第三部分我很抱歉
I'm so sorry about segment three.
下次我们会给那鸸鹋戴上尿片
Next time we put the emu in a diaper.
-等我电话  -至于贾斯汀的那个节目
- I'll call you. - Oh, the box-in-box with Justin...
-怎样  -太棒了  我很喜欢
- Yeah. - Looked great. I loved it.
-那就好  -我觉得我们可以...
- Good, good. - Listen, I think we should...
你是去参加定向越野  不是去图书馆
Um... you're going orienteering not librarying.
你觉得有必要带那么多书吗
You sure you want to take that many books?
对于五天的行程来说太多了吗
Overambitious for a 5-day trip?
到时候你的行李可是要你自己背着
You're gonna be responsible for your own pack.
你应该学学莎卡嘉薇亚[印第安女探险家]
I think you're supposed to be more Sacagawea
而不是一副文人学者的样子
than a scholarly reader.
再说了  你看看这么多的纸张
Besides, look at all those pages,
-树木们会找你报仇的  -理查德
- the trees might want revenge. - Richard.
怎么了
What's wrong?
鲍比·曼死了
Bobby Mann is dead.
什么  出什么事了
What? What happened?
据说他是心脏病发作
They're saying he had a heart attack.
我告诉你
I'm telling you, the guy
他说有人想置他于死地
said that somebody wanted him dead,
结果他就真的死了
and then he ends up dead.
这绝不仅仅是个巧合
That can't be a coincidence.
鲍比·曼有心脏病史
Bobby Mann had a history of heart disease,
再说了  验尸报告证实
and on the autopsy reports,
他的死亡确实是心脏病发所致
it states that the cause of death was a heart attack.
这也绝不会是巧合吧
That can't be a coincidence either.
是蕾妮验的尸吗
Did Lanie do the autopsy?
不是  但是她把报告寄过来了
No, but she sent it to me.
有个人在遛狗时
Okay, a guy was walking his dog,
看到曼一个人瘫倒在人行道上
saw Mr. Mann collapse on the sidewalk alone.
没有任何刺穿的伤痕  没有淤青
But there's no puncture wounds, no bruising,
而且毒性检验也一切正常
and the tox panel came back negative.
没有谋杀的迹象  卡塞尔
There's no foul play, Castle.
我今天早上和他的制片人谈了
I talked to his producer this morning.
她说曼十二点四十五的时候开着他的
She said that Mann left the studio at 12:45
布加迪威航[大众名车]离开的片场
in his Bugatti Veyron.
那车价值两百万
That's a $2-million car.
而四点五十的时候  他是在离家
He collapsed on foot a few blocks
-几个街区的地方步行时瘫倒的  -那又怎样
- from his house at 4:50. - So?
那车去哪儿了
So where's the car?
他可是个亿万富翁  卡塞尔
He's, like, a gazillionaire, Castle.
他说不定就是把车停在某个地方
He probably just parked it and
然后等别人第二天早上把车取回来
expected someone else to pick it up the next morning.
在我那本《斯道姆集结》里  那位前任克格勃
In my book "Gathering storm", the former KGB official
就是被一种检测不到的毒药杀死的
killed with an undetectable poison
导致心脏骤停的毒药
that stopped the heart.
说不定这事就发生在曼身上呢
What if that's what happened to Mann?
需要提醒你  你是依靠编造故事为生的
Need I remind you that you make up stuff for a living,
现实中根本没有这种毒药
and there is no such poison in real life,
如果真有这东西  那恐怕会有无数
and if there was, there would be a whole slew
愤怒的小夫妻可以逃过谋杀的罪名了
of angry spouses who'd be getting away with murder?
你就不能让蕾妮再仔细验一遍吗
Could you just have Lanie take a closer look?
求你了
Please.
你知道我为了这事
You know how many strings
动用了多少私人关系吗  卡塞尔
I had to pull for this, Castle?
如果我猜错了  我会为这个城市做出补偿
If I'm wrong, I'll reimburse the city.
关这个城市鬼事  你亏欠的是我
To hell with the city. It's me you're gonna owe.
你可以用水疗消费券  珠宝或者现金来补偿我
I take spa certificates, jewelry and cash.
遵命  那是什么
Duly noted. What's that?
鲍比·曼被送过来的时候
The contents of Bobby Mann's pockets
口袋里的东西
when he was brought in.
我去看看化验室有什么结果
I'm gonna a go check on the labs.
好的
Okay.
你干嘛呢
What are you doing?
这叫调查取证  你有空也该试试
It's called investigating. You should try it.
我通常只在有案子的时候才做这事
I usually wait until there's a crime.
手机  钱夹
Cell phone, money clip.
他先用张纸包住了口香糖
He stuck a piece of gum to a paper
才放进了口袋里
before he put it in his pocket.
这证明他死前没有乱扔垃圾
One of his last acts was not littering.
没错  但是这张纸上有一个词--"TORY"
Yes, but there's a word on this paper--"TORY."
说不定是个神秘女子呢
Could be a mystery woman.
厉害啊  卡塞尔  本案就此取得重大突破
Wow, Castle. Cracking this case wide open.
看这个  他的随手笔记
Hey, it's his idea notepad.
这是他昨晚说的那个笑话
This is a joke from last night.
"慈善高尔夫  他第一次抽身"
"Charity golf. First time he's pulled out in years."
你有没有意识到你正在调查的
Do you realize that you are
只是一次心脏病发作啊
now investigating a heart attack?
怎么了
What?
二十年来他的招牌台词
His signature line of 20 years,
"魅力男生  欢乐相约明晚"
"The boys'll be back on duty tomorrow night,"
看上去他是想改一改这句话了
looks like he was thinking of changing it.
"亲密团队  欢乐相约明晚"
"The crew will be back on duty tomorrow night."
也许他只是想把话说的时髦点儿
Maybe he was trying to make it hipper.
咱们也该弄一句招牌台词
We should have a signature line.
"她全副武装  他散播恐慌"
She's armed, he's dangerous.
-不要  -不要  那就
- No. - No. How about
"罪案终结的崭新篇章"
a whole new chapter in crime solving?
-"篇章"  有深度吧  -没有
- Chapter. Get it? - No.
我把所有标准规定以外的
Okay, I ran every extra tox screen
毒性化验都做了一遍
outside of standard protocol.
全是阴性  没有任何已知有毒物质的痕迹
All negative, no trace of any known poisonous substance.
听到啦  卡塞尔
Okay, Castle?
出门时别忘了给法医小费哦
Don't forget to tip your M.E. on the way out.
先别急着走
Ah, not so fast.
第二次毒性检验检测到了酪胺的成分
Secondary tox panel detected traces of tyramine,
它本身对人体是无害的
which is harmless,
但它的存在让我提高了警觉
but it's presence raised a red flag for me.
于是我又多做了一些化验
So I ran some more tests.
-鲍比·曼在服用苯乙肼  -苯乙肼
- Bobby Mann was taking phenelzine. - Phenelzine?
-一种抗抑郁处方药  -也就是说?
- A prescription drug for depression. - So?
苯乙肼是属于一种
So phenelzine is in a class of drugs
军方管制类药物
called M.A.O. Inhibitors
有着很严格的服用禁忌
that have powerful contra-indicators.
你是说食物与药物互相冲突
You mean drug interactions?
这种冲突是可以致命的
In this case, interactions that can kill.
军方管制类药物不能和任何
M.A.O. Inhibitors contra-indicate with
发酵过的东西同时服用  红酒  啤酒
anything fermented-- wine, beer,
还有特定种类的奶酪
certain kind of cheeses.
即使是很小的含量也会引发血压骤升
Even the smallest amount can trigger a hypertensive crisis.
这不和那种无法检测的
Oh! Almost like an undetectable
导致心脏骤停的毒药差不多嘛
poison that stops the heart.
这又不能说明他是被谋杀的
Which doesn't mean that he was murdered.
他说不定只是不小心吃了或者喝了
He could've accidentally eaten or drank something
某些他不该碰的东西
he shouldn't have.
我也是这么想的
That's what I thought.
所以我检测了一下他的肠道残余物
So I ran the contents of his intestines.
在他死前的几小时
In the hours prior to his death,
他摄入了三种物质
he ingested three substances--
-某种甜食  比如说糖块  -或者口香糖
- Something sugary, like hard candy... - Or chewing gum.
没错
There you go.
还发现有蔓越莓汁和甜醋
Also cranberry juice and balsamic vinegar.
甜醋是经过发酵的
Which is fermented.
而且除此以外没有任何可能添加了
And there was no trace of anything
甜醋的食物残余
that you would find balsamic on--
没有鸡肉  没有鱼肉  没有意粉
No chicken, no fish, no pasta.
只可能是蔓越莓汁
Just the cranberry juice.
蔓越莓汁可以轻易掩盖掉
Which could've easily masked the color
甜醋的颜色和气味
and the taste of the balsamic vinegar.
你的意思是
So you're saying
有人知道鲍比·曼的饮食禁忌
that somebody knew about Bobby Mann's condition,
在他的蔓越莓汁里偷偷加了甜醋
slipped balsamic vinegar into his cranberry juice,
并且知道这会置他于死地
knowing that it would kill him?
这绝非意外  鲍比·曼是被谋杀的
This was no accident. Bobby Mann was murdered.
鲍比  你说的果然没错
Well, Bobby, you were right.
没有犯罪现场  没有明确的位置
No crime scene, no clear place
来展开调查
to begin the investigation.
你说投毒案是不是太有意思了
Don't you just love poisonings?
尤其是这种没有毒药的投毒案
Especially a poisoning without poison.
这个凶手十分聪明
Whoever did this was very smart.
他所用的凶器几乎可以在
He chose a murder weapon that's probably
城里一半的厨房里找到
in half the kitchens in the city.
好在咱们也够聪明
Good thing we're smart, too.
谢谢  蕾妮的电话
Thanks. That was Lanie.
根据军方管制药物与食物冲突的致命程度
Based on possible rates of fatal M.A.O.I. interactions,
她可以把下毒时间范围缩小到
she was able to narrow the window of poisoning down
凌晨一点半到四点半之间
between 1:30 and 4:30 in the morning.
也就是说...
That makes...
这里
this...
就是投毒时间区
our kill zone--
一点半到四点半
1:30 to 4:30
还有什么
What else?
化验室说曼口袋里的
Well, the lab said that
口香糖上没有任何
there was no traces of cranberry juice
蔓越莓汁或者甜醋的成分
or balsamic vinegar in the gum we found in Mann's pocket.
所以他一定是在被投毒前吃的口香糖
So he must have chewed that before he was poisoned.
我们知道他是在十二点四十五离开片场的
Well, we know he left the studio at 12:45.
也就是说他不是在那里被下毒的
Which means he wasn't poisoned there.
我们还知道他家里的安全监控录像显示
And we know that his home security records
他一直没有回去过
show that he never made it there.
凌晨十二点四十五到四点五十
12:45 to 4:50 in the morning,
开着车走的  被发现时却是步行的
leaves in his car, is found on foot.
那么他在这段时间里干什么去了
So what was he doing that whole time?
另外  曼跑车里的
So the vehicle locator
车载定位器没有发出任何信号
in Mann's Bugatti is not sending a signal.
也许是在某个地下停车场
Probably in an underground parking garage.
也就是说车可能在任何地方
Which means it could be anywhere.
查一下他的手机
Check his cell phone,
看他昨晚有没有打过任何电话
see if he made any calls last night,
然后再去他的豪宅看看
and then go to his brownstone.
我和卡塞尔
Castle and I will head
去片场看看有没有什么线索
to the studio and see what we can dig up there.
-还有  -什么
- Oh, guys. - Yeah.
别提到谋杀二字
No talk of murder.
咱们对媒体瞒得越久
The longer we can keep this
调查就可以进行地更顺利
away from the press, the better off we'll be.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
我真不知道他昨晚节目结束以后去哪了
I don't know where he went after the show last night.
你们问这个干嘛
What is this about anyway?
我以为鲍比
I thought Bobby...
是死于心脏病发作
died of a heart attack, right?
我们只是在帮验尸官收集一些遗漏的信息
We're just tying up loose ends for the coroner.
曼先生最近状态如何
How was Mr. Mann acting recently?
你有发现什么异常吗
Did you notice anything unusual?
没有  他很好
No. He was great.
除了昨天
Uh... except yesterday.
-昨天发生什么了  -我也不知道
- What happened yesterday? - I don't know.
他整个早晨都把自己锁在办公室里
I mean, he spent the morning locked up in his office alone.
剩下的时间他都很焦虑不安
And then the rest of the day, he was agitated
而且表现地很奇怪
and he was acting weird.
-怎么个奇怪法  -疑心重重的
- Weird how? - Paranoid.
他还问我有没有听到什么传言
At one point he asked me if I had heard anything,
我问他关于什么的  他只是耸了耸肩
and I said, "About what?" And he just shrugged it off.
你有注意到他在服用强效抗抑郁药吗
Were you aware that he was on powerful antidepressants?
说实话  这件事上他很注重隐私
I mean, he tried to be very private about it,
但他服药期间  必须得戒酒
but when he went on them, he had to quit drinking,
于是大家都很好奇
and people wondered why.
所以事情就传开了
So word got around.
你不会认为他是因为这个被害的吧
You don't think that's what killed him, do you?
吃了什么东西  或者喝了什么
Something he ate or-- or drank?
他很谨慎的
He was very careful.
如我之前所说  我们只是跟进一下
Like I said, we're just following up.
我总是望向帷幕的那一端  知道吗
I keep looking over at that curtain, you know,
等着他从那走过来
waiting for him to walk through...
就好像这一切不过是个宣传噱头
like this was all one big publicity stunt.
你们两个关系很好  是吗
The two of you were close, right?
很久之前就是好朋友
Since before all this.
那时是在越南  我们都还很年轻
Since we were just kids together back in 'nam.
就是说如果出了什么事他会告诉你
So he would've told you if there was anything wrong?
出什么事
Like what?
比如说他担心他的身体和精神状况
Like if he was concerned for his well-being.
为什么问这些
What's this all about?
我以为他是死于心脏病发作
I-I thought he died of a heart attack.
只是一些例行问话  迈克菲先生
Just routine questioning, Mr McPhee.
对了  有人说最近他显得有点
You know, some of the people said that he seemed
坐立不安
a little agitated recently.
你这么一说  他是有些心事重重
Come to think of it, he was a little preoccupied.
昨晚节目结束之后我问他怎么了
I asked him about it after the show last night,
但是他坚持说他很好
but he insisted he was fine.
汉克
Hank.
老伙计  我很抱歉
Man, I am so sorry.
噩梦的确是会发生的
Nightmares really happen. Huh?
是啊  你认识米基吗
Yeah. You know Mickey--
《深夜脱口秀》的主持人  在我们节目之后播出
host of "Late Talk", right after our show?
当然认识  很喜欢你的节目
Yes, of course. I'm a big fan.
我很喜欢战利品轮盘赌那个板块
I love your whole "Booty Roulette" gag.
-真是不错  我是里克  -卡塞尔
- That's great. I'm Rick. - Castle.
是的  昨晚看到你上节目了
Yeah. Saw you on the show last night.
-我是凯特·贝克特探长  -很高兴认识你
- I'm Detective Kate Beckett. - Nice to meet you.
你们两个知道鲍比在节目结束之后
So do either of you know where Bobby went
去哪里了吗
after the show last night?
我们在为尸检报告调查他最后几个小时的行踪
We're trying to track his last hours for the coroner's report.
不知道
No clue.
我记得他好像提到要去见他的前妻
I think he said something about going to see his ex-wife.
他说去见哪个了吗
Did he say which one?
他有几个前妻啊
How many ex-wives did he have?
六个  年龄在二十五岁到五十岁之间
6, ranging in ages from 25 to 50.
就好像是每隔五年  他就换一个更年轻的
It seems every five years, he traded in for the latest model.
与其说他是娶了她们倒不如说他是租用了她们
So he didn't so much marry them as lease them.
我在系统里查了这六个名字
So I ran all their names through the system,
猜猜谁有案底
and guess what popped up.
看起来第五任前妻因为与鲍比
Seems wife number five here was arrested
在市中心的一家餐馆
over an altercation with Bobby
-发生口角而被捕  -她有疯子的眼睛
- at a restaurant uptown. - She's got crazy eyes.
还有发现
Well, there's more.
根据她居住的那栋大楼门卫的口供
According to the doorman in her building,
鲍比·曼昨晚节目之后去过那
Bobby Mann was there last night after the show.
曼夫人
Mrs. Mann,
你上次见到你的前夫是什么时候
when was the last time you saw your ex-husband?
大概是在一年前
About a year ago...
在法庭上
in court.
他对我申请了限制令
He took out a restraining order against me.
根据投诉来看
Well, according to the complaint,
你的确是威胁要杀死他
you did threaten to kill him.
我可不记得我说了些什么
Well, I don't really remember what was said.
"我希望你死掉  你这个黄鼠狼"
"I wish you were dead, you little weasel."
他在和一个更年轻的女人约会
He was dating a younger woman,
她长得跟我一模一样
and she looked just like me.
怎么不去和其他的前妻说去
Tell that to his previous wife.
-你了解他有饮食禁忌吗  -当然
- Were you aware of his dietary restrictions? - Sure.
不能吃发酵的东西  吃了会引发心脏病
Nothing fermented or it could give him a heart attack.
怎么了  你们觉得我和他的死有关系
Why? You think I had something to do with it?
你说说看  曼夫人  你住所的门卫说
You tell me, Mrs. Mann. According to your doorman,
鲍比昨晚在你的大楼出现过
Bobby showed up at your building last night.
-是吗  -辛迪  我们知道见过他
- He did? - Cindy, we know you saw him.
你们怎么知道他不是去看芭芭拉的
How do you know he wasn't there to see Barbara?
芭芭拉
Barbara?
他的第一任妻子
His first wife.
她在那座大楼也有套公寓
She's got an apartment in the building, too.
我们都是靠离婚协议得到的公寓
We both got 'em in the divorce settlement.
鲍比是那栋楼的联合业主
Bobby co-owned the building.
是的  我昨晚见过鲍比
Yeah, I saw Bobby last night.
他大概是凌晨一点来的
He came by around 1:00 in the morning,
像往常一样把我吵醒
woke me up as usual.
他总是这样半夜突然出现吗
Did he often surprise you in the middle of the night?
我是那个在他成名之前
I was the one woman who fell in love with him
还很穷的时候爱上他的女人
before all the fame and the money.
每当他感觉没有安全感的时候  他就会过来
Whenever he felt insecure, he came around.
大多是老生常谈
Mostly it was the same old stuff--
他节目收视率下降了  他年龄大了之类的
His ratings were down or... he was getting old.
但是昨晚
But last night...
怎么了
What?
有点不对头
It was different.
他看起来像是鬼上身了似的
He looked... haunted.
他说有事情要发生
He said something was going on,
不好的事情
something awful.
-要发生什么  -他不肯告诉我
- What was going on? - He wouldn't tell me.
他问我是否觉得他是个好人
He asked me if I thought he was a good person.
我拉着他的手说  鲍比
And I held his hand and I said, "Bobby,
你是个糟糕的丈夫
you're a lousy husband,
但你绝对是个真男人
but you're a hell of a man."
之后他就走了
Then he left.
什么时候
At what time?
一点十五左右
Around quarter after 1:00.
他说他要去哪里了吗
Did he say where he was going?
没有
No.
我以为他要回家的
I thought he was going home.
有不好的事情要发生
Something awful was going on.
他知道有人要对他下毒手
He knew someone was after him.
但是他既没告诉他的前妻也没告诉他的好朋友
But he doesn't tell his ex-wife or his best friend.
反而告诉了我
Instead he tells me.
也许是因为他知道
Maybe it's because he knew
你在和警察一起工作
you were working with the cops.
告诉我  我是个好人吗
Tell me I'm a good person?
就好像他干了什么为人所耻的事情
Like he was doing something he was ashamed of.
邻居确认了芭芭拉·曼的说法
Neighbors confirm Barbara Mann's story.
有人看到鲍比在凌晨一点十五离开她的公寓
One of them saw bobby leave her apartment at 1:15 a.m.
那个时间在我们的投毒时间区之外  就是说
That's outside of our kill zone, which means
我们还要搞清楚他接下来去了哪里
we need to figure out where he went to next.
去查一查这个地区所有的车库
Let's canvass all the garages in the area,
看看能不能找到曼的车
see if we can find Mann's car.
还要查查他的财产情况
And let's also look into his financials
看看有没有异常  毒品  赌博和嫖娼之类的
for the usual secrets-- drugs, gambling, prostitution.
就这些
Okay.
你好
Hello.
艾丽  你好
Ellie? Hi.
艾丽·梦露  节目上那个
Ellie Monroe, from the show.
是啊  我知道
Yeah. No, I know.
我了解
I understand.
我认为这是个好主意
No, I think that's a-a great idea.
好的
Yeah.
好  我在那和你碰面
Okay, I'll meet you there.
再见
Bye.
艾丽·梦露
Ellie Monroe, huh?
她对鲍比的遭遇感到很伤心
Yeah, she's pretty upset about this whole
因为我们是他最后的嘉宾
Bobby Mann thing, that we were his last guests.
她觉得我们聚一聚
She thinks it would be comforting
-对彼此都是个安慰  -"安慰"
- if we were to be together. - "Comforting"?
现在时髦的小青年都换这个说法了吗
Is that what the cool kids call it these days?
天啊
Wow.
你真是愤世嫉俗
You are so cynical.
知道吗  有时悲剧发生之后
You know, sometimes after a tragedy,
两个人只是想要在一起
two human beings just need to--to be with each other
没有其他的想法  就是想让对方
just for no other reason than to show each other
感到一些理解和支持
some understanding and support.
我很高兴我能安慰你
I'm just glad I can be comforting.
早安啊  探长
Good morning, Detective.
不是吧
Really?
怎么了
What?
不要用"刚上过床"的腔调说话  好不好
Lose the "I just got laid" voice, all right?
你说什么呢
What are you talking about?
我是受过训练的警探  你就不用否认了
I am a trained detective, so don't bother denying it.
好吧
Okay, fine.
怎么  一点都不否认吗
Oh, so now you're not denying it?
你刚刚告诉我不要否认的
You just told me not to.
伙计们  找到那辆车了吗
Hey, guys. Any news on the car?
在芭芭拉·曼居住大楼附近的车库
Nothing at any of the garages near
没有任何发现
Barbara Mann's building.
我们询问了周围饭店的停车场
So we checked restaurant valets in the area.
鲍比花了一百元雇一个莫扎特餐厅的服务员
Bobby paid the guy at Mozart's 100 bucks
在拜访前妻的这段时间帮他看车
to keep it close while he ran up to his ex.
目击证人说他是在一点半之前离开的
Witness says he left a little before 1:30.
六十一街和中央公园西门
61st and Central Park west.
之后他去了哪里
Where did he go after that?
也许可以查查那个地区的交通监控录像
Maybe check traffic cams in the area.
开着那种跑车的人
A guy in a sports car like that
也许会闯红灯被拍下来
might have blasted through some red lights.
好吧  像是在撞大运  不过还是试一试吧
Yeah. It's a bit of a hail mary, but it's worth a try.
或许我们用不着交通监控录像
Maybe we don't need traffic cams.
问问大街上的人就可以了
Why not just the man on the street?
我是说  名人开着辆布加迪威航
I mean, a celebrity in a Bugatti Veyron? Come on.
大家可不仅仅是注意到
People aren't just gonna notice that.
他们会谈论这件事的  确切的说是微博
They are going to talk about it, or more specifically, tweet.
看吧
And...
找到了
Booyah.
凌晨一点三十七  鲍比·曼 FTW
1:37 a.m. Bobby Mann F.T.W.
刚刚看到他把飞船一样的跑车
"Just saw him driving some spaceship car
开进百老汇街和五十七街的一个车库
into a garage at Broadway and 57th."
这就去
Ooh. On it.
-FTW  -为了胜利
- "F.T.W."? - "For the win."
意思是我的微博抢了你的微博的风头
It means, uh, "My tweet kicks your tweet's butt."
我说  贝克特
Come on, Beckett.
你要跟上潮流  和时髦小青年混一下
You gotta keep up. Hang with the cool kids.
我想这是找你的
I believe this is for you.
我  电话给我
Um, I'll just-- um, I'll just take that.
我接一下电话
I'm just gonna... take that. Mm-hmm.
等我一会
Pardon me one sec.
你好  艾丽
Hey, Ellie.
好的
Yes, yes.
昨晚真是很愉快  不是吗
Last night was great, wasn't it?
好的  我很乐意
Yeah, I'd love to.
今晚  当然可以
Tonight? Sure.
好的  到时候见
All right. I'll see you then.
更多"安慰"吗
More comforting?
百老汇街1525号的车库确认
Parking garage at 1525 Broadway confirms
鲍比·曼凌晨一点三十七停车入库
Bobby Mann pulled in at 1:37 a.m.
一直就没来取车
And he never came back for his car.
百老汇街1525号是什么地方
And what's at 1525 Broadway?
米基·瑞德的能看到公园风景的顶楼公寓
The park-view penthouse of Mickey Reed,
社交广泛而又和蔼可亲的深夜脱口秀主持人
the gregarious and affable host of "Late Talk."
米基  真是糟糕
Oh, Mickey... not so fine.
门卫一点四十五让鲍比进入他的住处
Doorman let Bobby up to his place at 1:45 a.m.
邻居投诉说有大声争吵的情况
Neighbors complained of a loud argument.
鲍比在两点之后不久离开
Bobby left a little after 2:00.
这么说米基对我们说谎了
So Mickey lied to us.
他在投毒时间区内
He saw Bobby somewhere right
见过鲍比
in the middle of our kill zone.
他会不会是做个好主人
You think he was a good host,
请鲍比喝了一杯饮料
offered Bobby a drink?
片场像是养老院一样
This set looks like an old-age home.
所有的东西都要升级  不要紫色和仿麂皮的
Everything needs to be updated--no purple, no suede,
不要假家具  把这个破玩意拿走
no faux finish--and get rid of this stupid thing.
已经开始重新装修了  瑞德先生
Measuring drapes already, Mr. Reed?
不管喜不喜欢  探长
Like it or not, Detective,
电视台希望我在下周悼念节目之后
The network wants me to take over
接过鲍比的时间段开始新节目
Bobby's time slot next week right after the tribute.
我知道这看起来有些无情
I know it seems callous,
不过鲍比肯定也希望这样
but it's what Bobby would've wanted.
-即使是踩着他的尸体  -你说什么
- Even over his dead body? - Excuse me?
那晚你见过曼  为什么要说谎
Why did you lie to us about seeing Mann the other night?
好吧
Okay.
我很抱歉
Look, I'm sorry,
不过我说谎是因为我不希望消息传出来
but I lied because I didn't want it getting out.
说你们两个争吵
That you two were fighting?
我接过他的衣钵已经很不容易了
It's hard enough filling the man's shoes around here.
我不希望小报报道我们在他去世那天
I don't need the tabloids writing about us getting into it
发生过争吵
on the night he died.
-不就是说谎嘛  没什么大不了的  -你对警察说了谎
- So I lied. So what? - So you lied to a cop.
我们现实一点吧
Let's be realistic.
他死于心脏病  不是吗
The guy died from a heart attack, right?
-怎么了  -的确是心脏病
- What? - It was a heart attack that was a result
触发原因是他体内的毒素  这毒素就是
of toxins in his system, toxins that he ingested
在你和他见面的时间内摄入的
somewhere around the time that you saw him.
你们是说我杀了鲍比
So you guys are saying I killed Bobby?
-为什么  -也不是什么秘密了
- Why? - Well, it's no secret,
你本来要接过他十一点半这个时间段的
You were supposed to get his 11:30 slot,
不过鲍比延长了他的合同
but Bobby extended his contract.
也许你等不及了
Maybe you couldn't wait.
-你听起来就和鲍比一样疯狂  -什么意思
- You sound as demented as Bobby. - What do you mean?
上次和他见面  我们还是好朋友呢
Last time I saw him, we're best of pals, right?
那天晚上他来找我  他一直大喊大叫
The other night he comes over, he's ranting and raving,
说我是个不守信誉的臭小子
talking about what a disloyal punk I've been.
-为什么  -我也不知道
-Why? - Man, I don't know.
他一直说他知道内幕
All he kept saying was, he knew things.
我就问  "你在说什么  鲍比"
And I'm like, "Bobby, what are you talking about?"
他冲出我家大喊  "你做了什么你知道"
He storms out saying I knew what I'd done.
鉴证组正在米基的公寓检查毒素的痕迹
CSU's at Mickey's apartment running a sweep for our toxin.
杀掉深夜秀的国王  自己登基
Killing the king of late-night to take his throne--
很有理查德三世[英国国王]的风范
It's very "Richard III."
很吸引当作家的我
It appeals to the writer in me.
你要咬一口吗
Did you want a bite of this?
告诉你  你们死定了
Hell, I'll sick god on you!
至于你  再也不要想上我电视网的节目
And you? I don't ever want to see you
你被封杀了  你
on my network again. You're banned! And you?!
我不认识你
I don't know you.
你们都是些无名小卒  我可以买下这个警局
You're all a bunch of nobodies! I could buy this precinct!
霍华德·维斯伯格  电视网的总裁
Howard Weisberg, president of the network.
他刚刚得知对米基的
He just found out about the search warrant
搜查令
for Mickey Reed.
他也发现了我们认为
And he also found out that we think
-鲍比·曼是被谋杀的  -怎么会
- Bobby Mann was murdered. - How?
被另外一家电视网抢了头条
Breaking news on a different network.
他自家明星的新闻被别人抢去了
The guy got scooped on his own star's murder.
现在想让媒体封口是不可能了
So much for keeping the press out.
你们两个的判断最好是对的
You two better be right about all this.
看着短信傻笑  不是吧
Text giggling? Really?
是阿丽克西斯  她看见潜鸟在进食
It's Alexis. She just saw a loon feeding.
有趣  我也看见了
Funny. So did I.
嘿  曼的布加迪跑车仍然在车库里
Hey. So... Mann's bugatti is still in the garage.
没有搜查令  我们可碰不了车
They won't let us touch it without a search warrant.
两百万美金的车
$2-million car.
很显然  比保险单上标的更贵
Apparently, it's worth more than their insurance policy.
你确定  他们不是在驾车兜风吗
You sure they aren't joyriding?
-好吧  找法官签搜查令  -好的
- All right, check with the judge.  - Mm-hmm.Okay.
如果这辆车还在车库里
If his car is still in the garage,
离开米基的家后  他去哪儿了
where'd he go after Mickey's place?
不会是太远的地方
Well, it couldn't have been very far.
嘿  莱恩  米基的门卫提到
Hey, Ryan. Did Mickey's doorman mention
曼离开时朝哪个方向去了吗
what direction Mann was headed when he left?
-嗯...  -南边
- Uh...  - South.
南边
South.
沿百老汇街从五十七街向南走
South on Broadway from 57th.
那里是剧场所在地
That's the theater district.
早晨两点  还没开门呢
Two in the morning? There's nothing playing then.
但是那里有小餐馆  俱乐部 饭店
Well, there's diners, there's clubs, there's restaurants.
除了毒药和口香糖之外
Well, other than the poison and the gum,
我们知道他没吃也没喝
we know he didn't eat or drink anything.
也许"TORY"是他去的一个地方
Maybe "TORY" is a place he went.
音乐学院  货仓  炼狱
Uh, conservatory, inventory, purgatory--
工厂  娱乐工厂  曼是个喜剧演员
Factory! The Comic Factory. Mann was a comedian.
他去了喜剧俱乐部
He went to a comedy club.
娱乐工厂在百老汇街和五十五街交口
Comic Factory is on, uh, 55th and Broadway.
隔两条街区的南边  他把口香糖
That's two blocks south. He put his gum in a--
粘在了一张娱乐工厂的传单上
in a piece of paper from a comic factory flyer.
-你是对的  -基于这一点
- You're right.  - Then from the forensics,
我们知道他在吐出口香糖之前
we know he didn't have the cranberry
既没有喝蔓越橘汁  也没有喝甜醋
or the balsamic before he spit it out.
因此他是在俱乐部时或之后被下毒的
So he was poisoned either at or after the club.
就是说米基·瑞德不是杀害鲍比的凶手
Then Mickey Reed didn't kill Bobby.
他不是我们的嫌疑人了
He's not our guy.
伙计们
Hey, guys.
去看一场喜剧表演怎么样
How do you feel about going to see a little comedy?
在喜剧界里  他是最脸熟的
The guy's got the most recognizable face in comedy.
我知道  我在俱乐部接到一个电话
Yeah, I know. Look, I got a call on the club phone.
来电显示的是鲍比的节目组
The caller I.D.'s from Bobby's Show.
对方向我打听我这里的一名喜剧演员
A guy asks about one of my comedians.
几小时后  有人过来看了那位演员的演出
Couple hours later, guy shows up to see that comedian,
不过他留着好笑的小胡子
but he's got a funny looking moustache
戴着棒球帽  看起来像是鲍比
and he's wearing a baseball cap. It looked like Bobby.
他有和人说话吗  有喝过东西吗
Did he talk to anyone? Did he have a drink?
没有  他坐在后面
No. He sat in the back,
他看完那位喜剧演员的表演后
left his drink ticket, and bolted out the side
丢下了换饮料的小票  就跑出去了
after watching the comedian he came to see.
这个喜剧演员有什么特别的吗
Anything special about this particular comedian?
安吉·桑塔纳
Angel Santana,
公认的明日之星
the proverbial rising star?
我想你们知道昨晚发生的那件事吧
I'm assuming you know about the incident that night?
什么事
What incident?
我是安吉·桑塔纳  晚安  各位
I'm Angel Santana. Good night, you all.
桑塔纳小姐
Ms. Santana.
我是埃斯波西托警探  这位是莱恩警探
I'm Detective Esposito. This is Detective Ryan.
你们好  谢谢能来这里
Oh, hey. Thanks for coming.
那天问我话的警官让我觉得案子破不了
The officer I talked to did not instill a lot of confidence.
能说说发生什么事了吗
You want to tell us about it?
没什么可说的  我表演的那晚
Not much to tell. During my set that night,
有人弄碎了我摩托车的尾灯
someone smashed my bike's taillight,
毁坏了挡泥板
banged up the fenders
在车身上刻了"午夜贱货"几个字
and scratched "Late-night bitch" into the tank.
我是说  这是什么意思
I mean, what does that even mean?
事实上  我们不是为你的摩托车而来的
Actually, we're not here about your bike.
桑塔纳小姐  你认识鲍比·曼吗
Ms. Santana, did you know Bobby Mann?
私人交往上  不认识  为什么
You mean personally? No. Why?
因为在他被杀的那个晚上
Well, because he came to see your act
他来这看了你的演出  知道为什么吗
on the night he was killed. Any idea why?
天啊  很可能是他毁了我的摩托
Wow. He probably trashed my bike.
我听说过他的伎俩
I've heard stories about him.
就因为有人上了他对头的节目
I know guys he's blackballed
他就会想方设法的排挤那人
just because they did his competitors' show.
你知道他找你麻烦
Is there any reason why
有什么特别的原因吗
he might have wanted to come after you?
上个月  他的制片人约我上他的节目
His producer tried to book me on his show last month,
但是米基·瑞德也想约我
but Mickey Reed wanted me, too.
我得做选择
I had to pick.
米基更合我的口味
Mickey felt more like my vibe.
俱乐部老板说鲍比在两点半离开
Club owner said Bobby left at 2:30,
吧台招待确认他没喝任何东西
and the bartender confirms he didn't drink anything.
这样只剩下两个小时
Which leaves us... two hours left
来解释这一系列奇怪的行为
to account for and a whole lot of strange behavior.
鲍比为什么去见一个不愿上他节目的
Why would Bobby go see a comedian
喜剧演员  还砸烂了她的摩托车
who didn't want to do his show and then bust up her bike?
名人不都比较疯狂和自恋吗
Aren't famous people crazy and narcissistic?
我不清楚  去问卡塞尔
I don't know. Gotta ask Castle.
卡塞尔去哪了
Where is Castle anyway?
我需要一件新衬衫
I'm gonna need some new shirts.
不要衬衫
No shirts.
早上好
Good morning.
没关系  卡塞尔  你不需要为我装成
It's okay, Castle. You don't have to pretend
心情不好的样子
to not be in a good mood for my sake.
我为什么要心情好
Why should I be in a good mood?
我是说...  我是作家
I mean... I'm a writer.
作家都很忧郁
We... famously brood.
我们...  我应该更忧郁一点
We... I should brood more.
你想要忧郁
You want to brood?
安吉·桑塔纳的摩托车上毫无线索
Forensics on Angel Santana's motorcycle are a bust.
没有指纹  什么也没有
There's no fingerprints. Nothing.
我们搞不清曼两点半后在哪儿
We have no idea where Mann was after 2:30.
他的车呢
What about his car?
莱恩和埃斯波西托拿到了搜查令
Ryan and Esposito got a warrant this morning.
但我们知道他是在停车后被下毒的
But seeing that he was poisoned after he parked it,
所以车上可能不会有什么线索
chances are we won't find anything.
而且  他的财产状况良好
And his financials were clear.
他一天支付的离婚赡养费
He pays more in alimony
比我整整一年赚的还多
in a day than I make in an entire year.
他的电话记录上也没什么线索
There's no red flags on his phone records.
我再次询问了他所有的同事
And I reinterviewed all of his colleagues.
没有人知道他为什么表现的如此多疑
No one has any idea why he was acting so paranoid.
如果有人真要杀你  你就不算是多疑
You're not paranoid if someone's actually trying to kill you.
托尼  我最喜爱的电影大亨最近如何
Hey, Tony! How's my favorite movie mogul?
是的  没错吧
Yes. Right?
她是妮基的最佳人选
She'd be perfect for Nikki.
好的  太棒了
Yes. Perfect.
谢谢
Thank you.
那是《希特热浪》的制片人
That's a "Heat Wave" producer.
不是关于艾丽·梦露的吧  对吗
That wasn't about Ellie Monroe, was it?
-是啊  怎么了  -哦
- Yeah, why?  - Oh.
怎么了
What?
那就解释了她为什么向你投怀送抱
That's why she was throwing herself at you.
她想让你推荐她  从而得到那个角色
She wanted you to recommend her for the part.
什么
What?
我要强调一下  她一点都不像妮基·希特
Oh, and for the record, she's nothing like Nikki Heat.
你只是无法忍受一个美丽的女演员
Oh, you just can't stand it that a beautiful actress
会对我产生兴趣
is actually interested in me.
我为什么要关心呢
Why would I care?
确切来说  这是个好问题
Exactly. That's a good question.
你为什么要关心呢
Why would you care?
-我才不会  -好吧  我要去拿咖啡
- I don't.  - Fine. I'm gonna go get some coffee.
好呀  我要回去工作
Fine. I've got work to do.
休息室在那边
Break room's that way.
-桌子这边  -贝克特
- Desk.  - Beckett.
卡塞尔  听听这个
Castle. Check this out.
我们刚调查了鲍比的车
We just finished the sweep of Bobby's car.
首先  这辆布加迪  极速换挡
First off, the Bugatti-- holy shift.
当你发动这辆车  那感觉就像是...
When you start this thing, you can feel it right in--
跟这车同样令人兴奋的是
But as exciting as the car is,
我想我们发现鲍比·曼坐立不安的原因了
I think we figured out why Bobby Mann was so tweaked.
我们在车的杂物箱里发现了这个
We found this in his glove compartment.
那是凯拉  鲍比脱口秀的实习生
That's Kayla. She's an intern at Bobby's show.
看来她不仅仅是实习而已
Looks like she was doing more than interning.
看看照片后面
You should check out the back.
如果他们发现  你就死定了
"If they find out, you're dead."
勒索  死亡恐吓及丑闻
Blackmail, death threats and scandal.
正好解释他行为怪异的原因
That explains why his behavior was so erratic.
也可能是他被杀的原因
And probably why he was killed.
是在上周
It was last week.
我加班为鲍比处理一些琐碎工作
I stayed late to help Bobby with some bits.
凯拉  你知道是谁偷拍的吗
Do you have any idea who took that, Kayla?
可能是节目的工作人员
Must be someone who works on the show.
那人刚好有相机
Who just happened to have a camera
抓拍到你们俩的奸情
and managed to catch the two of you in the act?
还是有人给他们通风报信
Or were they tipped off maybe?
你在勒索鲍比吗
Were you blackmailing Bobby?
我的天啊  不是
Oh, my god. No.
他的年纪可比你大三倍
He's three times your age,
你又是节目组的实习生
and you are an intern on the show.
这会给他制造难堪和丑闻
That adds up to embarrassment and scandal,
我敢肯定他会付一大笔钱来摆平
which I'm sure he'd pay a lot to avoid.
不  我绝不会这么做
No, I would never do that.
我们是真心相爱的
We were in love.
相爱  真的吗
In love? Really?
你们俩在一起多久了
And... how long were the two of you together?
到周一为止刚好三个星期
Three weeks this past Monday.
还有谁知道
Who else knew?
没人知道  我们是地下情
No one. Bobby and I kept it a secret.
我们不希望我妈妈发现
We didn't want my mom to find out.
你妈妈
Your mom?
你妈妈是谁
Who's your mom?
他竟然在我眼皮底下跟我女儿乱搞
He was banging my daughter right under my nose?
-我要杀了他  -他已经死了
- I will kill him!  - He's already dead.
那我要让他再死一遍
Well, I will kill him again.
我不在乎  尸体在哪
I don't care. Where's the corpse?
马克斯夫人  我们
Ms. Marks, we just--
凯拉  马上到我办公室  快点
Kayla, my office, now! Move it!
-妈妈  你不明白  -快去
- Mom, you don't understand  - Move it.
你知道  如果这事传出去
You realize, if this gets out,
会毁了鲍比的声誉
it'll destroy Bobby's reputation.
我们并不想添乱
We're not trying to add to an already difficult situation.
我们只想找到凶手
We're just trying to find the killer.
鲍比不是个完人
Bobby wasn't an angel,
但纵观他的一生
but you look at the man in his entirety.
他值得流芳百世
He deserves to be remembered with grace.
这一行被金钱  名声和野心所笼罩
This business gets clouded by money, fame, ambition.
鲍比真正在乎的
The only thing that Bobby really cared about
就是给人们带来欢笑
was making people laugh.
拍这照片的人  不是这里的工作人员
Well, whoever took this either works for this show
就是可以自由进出大厦的人
or had access to this building.
也许是有人手头拮据
And maybe it was someone in a financial jam
想挣个外快
who was looking to score a quick buck.
也可能有人对鲍比怀恨在心
Or maybe it's someone with a grudge against Bobby.
我想不出谁会这么干
I can't imagine anyone doing that.
他是位好上司  大家都爱他
He was a great boss. Everyone loved him.
没错  显然他也爱他们
Yeah, and apparently, he loved them back.
好吧  等珍妮教训完凯拉
Okay. Uh, Janine can get you a list of everyone on the crew
她会给你一份工作人员名单
once she's done yelling at Kayla.
可怜的孩子  谁能想到呢
Poor kid. Who knows?
她有可能是他第七任妻子的
She might have ended up being number seven.
有什么发现
What have we got?
既然我们怀疑是勒索
Well, once we suspected blackmail,
我就又查看了他的账户
I ran through his financials again.
我以为财产情况没问题
I thought they were clean.
原先没问题  但复查后发现这个
Well, they were, but going back, we found this.
他花了十万美金翻修厨房
He spent 100 grand on a kitchen reno.
完全合法  但我们搜查了他的住所
Totally legitimate, but we searched his brownstone--
发现他并未翻修厨房
And he wasn't renovating his kitchen.
那是谁收了这十万美金
So who was on the receiving end of the 100 grand?
扎克·罗宾森
Zach Robinson.
这坏人的名字太妙了
Ooh. Good bad-guy name.
狡猾的"Z"  冷酷的"K"
Snakey "Z", Hard "K".
甚至还有"抢劫"在里边[rob有抢劫之意]
Even has "Rob" in it.
前科也符合坏人的标准
Good bad-guy rap sheet, too.
以前是个卑劣的私家侦探
Former lowlife private investigator.
我认得这家伙
I remember this guy.
他曾经有一些名人客户
He had some celebrity clients back in the day.
他臭名昭著  专挖他人丑闻
He was known for digging up dirt on folks
并以此谋生
and turning it into a personal payday.
他靠敲诈  窃听  诈骗和勒索
He did a nickel on multiple counts of extortion,
挣了一大笔钱
wire tapping, racketeering and blackmail.
罗宾森肯定是通过内部人员
Well, Robinson must have gotten the picture
搞到这张照片
from somebody on the inside.
没错  认为是捞钱的好机会
Sure. Figured it was worth a fast buck.
但如果鲍比给钱了  为什么还杀他呢
But if Bobby paid, why would he kill him?
鲍比发现罗宾森就是勒索人
Bobby figured out that Robinson was a blackmailer,
就威胁要向警方举报他
and then he threatened to take him to the cops.
鲍比把罗宾森逼急了  罗宾森就反击了
Bobby pushes, Robinson pushes back harder.
-去把他找来  -说得容易做起来难
- Let's go pick him up.  - Easier said than done.
埃斯波西托已经去过他的住所了
Esposito already ran down his last known address.
罗宾森下落不明
Robinson's in the wind.
那我们就继续找
Well, let's keep looking.
好的
Yeah.
你是个坏人  扎克·罗宾森
You are a bad man, Zach Robinson.
你这个下流  淘气  一无是处的勒索者
A dirty, naughty, no-good blackmailer.
你都在床上进行审问吗  希特探长
Do you do all your interrogations in bed, Detective Heat?
你觉得这很可笑吗  罗宾森
You think this is funny, Robinson?
好吧
Okay, okay.
不  我会照你说的做  妮基
No, I'll do whatever you want, Nikki.
好了  这还差不多
Okay. That's more like it.
你真是太可爱了
You are so sweet.
还很聪明
And brilliant.
说得对
Guilty.
你在想什么
What are you thinking?
没什么
Nothing.
挺可笑的
It's ridiculous.
什么  说说看  我想知道
What? Come on. Tell me. I want to know what goes on
你那不可思议的大脑在想些什么
inside that incredible mind of yours.
既然你这么说
Well, since you put it that way.
与我共事的一位朋友
I have this... friend at work
认为你和我一起的唯一原因
who thinks that the only reason you're with me is,
就是为了得到这个电影角色
you know... for the part in the movie.
真的吗
Really?
你这朋友的依据是什么
What does this friend of yours base that on?
我很抱歉
You know what? I'm-- I'm sorry.
我不该提这事的
I shouldn't have repeated that.
-这朋友认识我吗  -不认识
- Does this friend know me?  - No.
他看了我什么报道就认为
Has he read anything about me that would make him think
我会利用潜规则获取角色
that I would prostitute myself for a role?
不  当然不是
No. Of course not.
你  我  他就是一个笨蛋
You--I--he's an idiot.
你知道一个女人
Do you have any idea
在好莱坞闯荡有多艰辛吗
how hard it is to be a woman in Hollywood?
艾丽
Ellie.
我
I--
没错
Oh, yeah.
他看起来像扎克·罗宾森
He looks like a Zach Robinson.
在哪找到他的
Where'd you find him?
在金神大赌场的双骰子赌桌
The boys caught up with him
抓到他的
at a craps table at Mohegan Sun.
辛苦得来的勒索钱财已经赌光了吗
Already gambling away his hard-earned blackmail money?
和你的小明星约会怎样了
So how was your date with your little starlet?
这次你是怎么看出来的
How can you tell this time?
像我说的  卡塞尔  干练的警探
Like I said, Castle... trained detective.
进展很不错
Well... it went lovely.
并不是因为你
No thanks to you.
这和我有关系吗
What did I have to do with it?
你用了绝地武士[星战角色]控制意志的招数
You pulled your Jedi mind trick on me.
你让我怀疑艾丽的真诚
You made me doubt Ellie's honesty.
我真蠢  告诉她你的想法  把她弄哭了
Foolishly, I told her what you said, made her cry.
卡塞尔  她是位演员
Castle... she's an actress,
专业的大话精
a professional liar.
流眼泪可是有薪水拿的
She's paid to cry on cue.
不
No.
我从没见过这张照片
I've never seen this picture before.
是吗
Really?
你确定没有用这张照片来勒索鲍比·曼?
You sure you didn't use it to blackmail Bobby Mann?
勒索
Blackmail?
你完全抓错人了  探长
You're fishing in the wrong pond, Detective.
那鲍比·曼存入你户头的
What about the 100 grand
十万美元作何解释
from Bobby Mann in your bank account?
我没抓错人吧
Am I in the right pond now?
那是服务费
That was for... services rendered.
我想韦氏词典没有把"勒索"
I don't think Webster's defines "Blackmailing"
定义为"服务"吧
as a service.
应该说是强制性的恐吓吧  "抢劫"先生
More like a coercive threat, Mr. Rob-inson.
不不  搞错了  我从来没有威胁过鲍比
No, no. No, no. I never threatened Bobby.
他雇用了我
He hired me.
做什么
To do what?
据我手下的调查  曼被谋害的当晚
My guys say that you don't have an alibi
你没有不在场证明
for the night that Mann was murdered.
开玩笑吧
You can't be serious.
是不是玩笑  谋杀审讯时自然见分晓
I guess it'll come out when we go to the murder trial.
判决如下  狱中生活快乐
Have a nice life... sentence.
什么  别这样  别这样
What? No, no. No, no. No, no, no, no, no, no.
是他来找的我
Look, he reached out to me.
说有活儿给我
Said he needed some work done.
什么样的"活儿"
What kind of work?
需要花很多钱的那种
The kind that you get paid a lot extra to do.
违法的
Something illegal.
这个
W-well...
听着  他觉得有人盯上他了
Okay, look, he thought that somebody was out to get him.
而他想要知道内情
He said he needed to know,
于是就雇我在某人的办公室里装窃听器
and so he paid me to bug a guy's office.
谁的办公室
Who?
-霍华德·维斯伯格  -电视台的总裁
- Howard Weisberg. - The president of the network?
很简单  鲍比把我弄进了办公楼
Easy gig, too. Bobby got me into the building.
什么时候的事
When was this?
-一周前  -录音带如何处置的
- Week ago. - What did you do with the recordings?
-已经快递给了鲍比  -何时
- I delivered the CDs to Bobby. - When?
就在
You know...
他死的那天早上
the morning before he died.
鲍比的制片人说
Bobby's producer said
当天早上  他曾把自己锁在办公室内
he locked himself in his office that morning.
-他在听录音  -之后
- He was listening to the recordings. - And then
大家说他就开始神经兮兮的
they said he started acting paranoid after that,
他究竟听到了什么内容
so what did he hear?
我可以走了吗
Am I good to go?
在曼的办公室找到录音
We found the recordings in Mann's office
和其它电影光盘混在了一起
mixed in with his DVD collection.
有没有发现曼为什么
Heard anything yet that would explain
要窃听他的上司
why Mann was listening in on his boss?
没有  就是一大堆关于宴请编剧  演员
Just a bunch of talk about setting up breakfasts, lunches,
导演的商务会谈的安排
dinners and drinks with writers, actors and directors.
勒索方面有何进展
Where are we on the blackmail?
警员正在调查能够进入演播室拍照
We got uniforms running down all show employees
的所有相关工作人员
who could've had access to the studio to take that photo.
过来听听这个
Yo. You guys are gonna want to hear this.
知道吗  让鲍比·曼见鬼去吧
You know what? To hell with Bobby Mann.
每晚他的节目都在赔钱
We're losing money on him every damn night.
-我要他滚蛋  -我们束手无策  不能炒他
- I want him out! - Our hands our tied. You can't fire him.
他还有五年的合同
He's got five years left on his contract.
那他挂了总可以吧
What if he drops dead, huh?
说真的  这家伙心脏不好
Seriously. The guy has got a bad heart.
让他滚蛋有这么难吗
How hard would it be to make him go away?
真是见鬼  米基·瑞德每天都在说
I mean, hell, I got Mickey Reed telling me every day,
他已经准备好了
he's ready to step in
只要鲍比·曼退位  他就立刻顶上
if we could just get Bobby Mann out the damn door.
难怪鲍比觉得米基靠不住
Well, no wonder Bobby thought Mickey was disloyal.
难怪他认为有人想他死
And no wonder he thought someone wanted him dead.
的确有人要他死
Someone did.
那他挂了总可以吧
What if he drops dead, huh?
说真的  这家伙心脏不好
Seriously. The guy has got a bad heart.
让他滚蛋有这么难吗
How hard would it be to make him go away?
看来你如愿以偿了  维斯伯格先生
Looks like you got your wish, Mr. Weisberg.
探长  这些窃听带是无法作为
Detective, none of the recordings
呈堂证供的
are admissible in court.
放轻松  伯特  我没有杀人
Oh, relax, Burt. I didn't kill anyone, okay?
等我真杀了  你再摆律师架子吧
Save it for when I actually do.
-探长  这是无心之言  -鲍比认为你是有意的
- Detective, I wasn't serious. - Bobby thought you were.
那他就不应该窃听我的办公室
Then maybe he shouldn't have been bugging my office.
私下里  电视台那些拿着高薪不出活的混蛋
Hell, in private, I issue a dozen death sentences a day
我一天至少十几次地诅咒他们去死
on underperforming, overpaid jackasses at my network.
我只是想把米基·瑞德的节目调至十一点半
Now what I wanted was Mickey Reed pulled to 11:30.
但是鲍比手持八千万违约金的合同
But Bobby had an $80-million penalty on his contract.
意味着你还得等五年
Which still had another five years left on it.
这几个月我的确向鲍比施压
Yeah. Now what I did was lean on Bobby for a few months
让节目要向年轻观众靠拢
to appeal to a younger audience.
但我做的最过分的
But the worst thing that
无非就是威胁说要炒掉他
I did was threaten to fire him
赔他八千万
and pay him the $80 mil.
维斯伯格先生  谋杀当晚的凌晨一点半
Mr. Weisberg, where were you between 1:30
至四点半  你在哪里
and 4:30 a.m. the night of the murder?
-你有权拒绝回答  -没事  伯特  别激动
- You don't have to answer that. - It's fine, Burt. Chill out.
-我在艾塞克斯酒店  -有证人吗
- I was at the Essex House Hotel. - Were you with anyone?
事实上我有证人  是位和我上床的女演员
As a matter of fact I was. This actress I was screwing
想在我的情景喜剧中捞个角色
wanted a part on one of my sitcoms.
我是通过鲍比的节目遇到她的
I met her after Bobby's show.
我要她的名字
I'm gonna need a name.
没问题  艾丽·梦露
Sure. Ellie Monroe.
谢谢你跑一趟  梦露小姐
Thank you for coming by Ms. Monroe.
应该的
Of course.
维斯伯格的不在场证明
Weisberg's alibi...
成立
is good.
说吧  一吐为快
Oh, go on. You can say it.
早就警告过你了
"I told you so."
不用了  我现在没有幸灾乐祸的心情
No, thanks. I'm actually not in the gloating mood.
他的不在场证明  让我们回到了起点
His alibi sets us back to square one...
勒索者是谁  我们依然没有头绪
Which means we have no idea who the blackmailer is,
也不知道曼为什么要去喜剧俱乐部
and we don't know why Mann went to the comedy club
为什么要砸坏安吉·桑塔纳的摩托车
and trashed Angel Santana's bike.
更别提找到凶手了
And we have no idea who the killer is.
好消息就是  我可以整晚工作
Well, the good news is, I can work all night.
没人可约了
No plans.
很晚了  我也有些累了
You know, it's late, and I'm kinda tired.
明早继续如何
How about we pick this up in the morning?
也好
All righty,then.
魅力男生  欢乐相约明天
And the boys'll be back on duty tomorrow,
常言道
to coin a phrase...
这是不对的
which would be inaccurate...
因为你不是男生
Because you are not a boy.
这是什么奇怪的搭讪吗
Is this some kind of a weird come-on?
我知道鲍比·曼
I think I know
去喜剧俱乐部的原因了
what Bobby Mann was doing at that comedy club.
也知道他为什么觉得自己是个很糟糕的人
I think I know why he thought he was an awful person.
我还知道谁杀了他
And... I think I know who killed him.
迈克菲先生
Mr. McPhee?
我正在看悼念专题节目的致词
I was just going over my notes for the tribute.
三十五年的友谊
35 years of friendship--
想找出最好的故事  真的很难
It's kinda hard to find just the right story to tell.
有什么可以效劳的
What can I do for you?
我们来给你这个
We just came by to give you this.
鲍比的随手笔记  觉得你应该会喜欢
Bobby's idea book-- We thought you might like it.
-谢谢  -我们也想问问
- Thanks. - We did have a
上面最后一页写的内容
question about what he wrote on the last page.
魅力男生  欢乐相约明晚
"The boys'll be back on duty tomorrow night."
事实是  他划掉了"男生"
Actually, he crossed out "Boys"
写上了"超级组合"和"亲密团队"
and wrote "Gang, Posse" and "Crew."
知道原因吗
Any idea why?
可能我们永远都不会知道了
I guess we'll never know.
我不这么认为
I wouldn't be too sure about that.
电视台给鲍比施压  让他作出改变
The network was pressuring Bobby to make a change.
甚至威胁说不改变就解雇他
They threatened to cancel him unless he did.
就在他被谋杀当晚
And the night that he was murdered,
他告诉芭芭拉  有些不好的事即将发生
he told Barbara that something awful was going on.
他还问她  自己是否是好人
He asked her if he was a good person.
他为什么那么说
Why would he say that?
因为凯拉这件事
Because of Kayla.
汉克  与凯拉无关
Not Kayla, Hank.
是因为你  他知道自己必须要开除你
Because of you. He knew that he had to fire you.
他知道如果要生存  就要找一位时髦的
He knew he needed to find someone younger and hipper
时下青年代替你
if he was gonna survive.
比如说安吉·桑塔纳
Someone like Angel Santana.
维斯伯格确认了
Weisberg confirmed that she was
她在最后的候选名单上
on the network's short list.
汉克  "魅力男生"招牌将不复存在
That's why it wasn't "Boys" anymore, Hank.
因为安吉是女生
'Cause Angel's a girl.
这太荒谬了  鲍比绝对不会炒我的
This is ridiculous. Bobby would never fire me.
-那你为什么杀了他  -我没有
- Then why did you kill him? - I didn't.
汉克  我们已经查了你的信用卡
We ran your credit cards, Hank.
他被谋杀当晚  你在一家
The night that he was murdered, you went
全天营业的杂货店里  买了两样东西
to a 24-hour grocery store and bought two things--
蔓越莓汁和甜醋
Cranberry juice and balsamic vinegar.
时间显示为凌晨一点五十六分
It's time stamped 1:56 a.m.
我敢肯定如果化验你的钥匙
And I'm betting if we test your keys,
会找到安吉·桑塔纳摩托车上的材质
we'll find metal from Angel Santana's motorcycle.
你在车上刻了"午夜贱货"
Where you scratched in "Late-night bitch."
他跟我说了
He told me...
那晚他离开演播室前说的
That night just before he left the studio...
他听到维斯伯格说了什么
How he'd heard Weisberg say
不做出改变的话  他的事业就毁了
they were gonna bury him unless he made a change.
三十五年了  我一直支持他
35 years, I had his back.
而他却像甩开众多前妻一样地甩开我
He was gonna toss me aside like one of his ex-wives,
当着全国观众的面羞辱我
humiliate me in front of the whole country.
我知道会有这一天  我发现了征兆
I knew it was coming. I saw all the little signs,
大厅里的尴尬时分
the awkward moments in the hall.
我把他和凯拉的照片发给他
I sent him that picture of him and Kayla
是要提醒他  他有把柄在我手上
to remind him of all the secrets I kept.
知道他说什么吗
You know what he said?
丑闻只会让收视更红
The scandal would only help his ratings.
你买了毒药
You bought your poison
并且尾随他去了俱乐部
and you followed him to the club.
他出来后我就当面质问他
I confronted him when he came out.
我让他不要甩开我们的心血
I told him not to throw away everything we'd built.
他说他帮不了我
He told me he couldn't save me.
有没有他  维斯伯格都要走年轻化路线
Weisberg was going younger with or without him.
既然你知道他无从选择
Well, if you knew he didn't have a choice,
为什么要杀他
why did you kill him?
因为他有选择
Because he did have another choice.
玉石俱焚
Go down with the ship!
我们一起体面地离开
We both go out gracefully,
鲍比会有八千万的赔偿
and Bobby gets 80 million bucks
这不比他陪小孩子耍猴戏强吗
instead of him continuing the show with some kid.
我陪他做了四千多集节目
I gave him over 4,000 shows,
无论他的笑话好笑与否
laughing at every lousy joke he cracked,
我都卖力去笑
whether they were funny or not.
上帝啊
Jeez.
你是如何下手的
So how did you manage it?
当我知道无法改变他的想法时
When I knew I couldn't change his mind,
我告诉他
I told him...
我能体谅他
I understood.
我们走到西区大道
We walked over to the West Side Highway,
坐在长椅上  看着海
sat on a bench, looked out at the water,
回忆我们的辉煌岁月
talked about what a great run we'd had.
然后我请他喝饮料
Then I offered him a drink.
他是我最好的朋友
He was my best friend.
对朋友下手...
You don't do that to your friend.
又一个实例证明
Yet another example of
工作与娱乐不能混淆
why you shouldn't mix business with pleasure,
哪怕是娱乐工作
even show business.
你是在说案子  还是说你自己
Are you talking about the case or yourself?
一针见血啊  探长
Touche, Detective.
要不要去享受一下胜利的汉堡
So you want to go for a victory lap and grab a burger?
-不行  得走了  有约  -你开玩笑吧
- Oh, can't. Gotta go. Big date. - You're kidding, right?
你还约那个艾丽·梦露
You're going out with Ellie Monroe even though
明知道她对你唯一感兴趣的就是
you know the only reason that she was interested in you
争取角色
was for a part?
难道你已经拉下了所有的面子
Have you lost all sense of human decency
抛弃了自尊  怎么了
and self-res-- What?
我是与阿丽克西斯有约
My big date... is with Alexis.
她的旅行结束了
She's getting back from her trip.
这样啊
Oh.
刚刚好  阿丽克西斯
Right on time, Alexis.
莎卡嘉薇亚
Oh, Sacagawea...
回来啦
has returned!
你不是莎卡嘉薇亚
And you are not Sacagawea,
请进
but come in.
谢谢
Thanks.
我要回洛杉矶了
I'm headed back to L.A.
我是来道歉的
And I just wanted to... say sorry.
谢谢  但事实上
Thanks. But the truth is,
我从未被利用地如此快乐过
I've never had so much fun being used.
随时恭候
You feel free to have at me anytime.
我想你会向制片人取消对我的推荐
Well, I guess you'll rescind your recommendation of me
这是我活该
to your producers, and that is the least I deserve--
不  托尼和我都觉得你很棒
No, Tony thinks you are great for it, and so do I.
我推荐你时  都没想到你的演技
You are a better actress than I thought
如此出色
when I recommended you.
你应该知道  我并非一直在演戏
Well, you should know, I wasn't acting the whole time.
我和你一样
Me neither.
谢谢  里克
Thanks, Rick.
保重
Take care.
你也保重
You, too.
再见
Bye.
爸  这是...
Dad, was that--
我的莎卡嘉薇亚回家了
My Sacagawea has returned!
老天  我的乖女儿  我真想你
Oh, my god. My best girl. I missed you so much.
老天  真高兴你回来了
Oh, my god. I'm so glad you're home.
爸  我也想你
I missed you, too, dad.
-你不是随口说说吧  -什么
- You're not just saying that, are you? - What--
-没什么  你饿了吧  -非常饿
- No, don't. Tell me you're hungry. - I'm starving.
来吧  讲讲旅途趣事
Come with me. Tell me everything.